Well, that was a perfect psalm for us to start this year with that, psalm is great for the
biblical text.
It is a prayer that you're already reading to the priesthood of Israel to pray over the
nation of Israel, and it is a prayer that I believe that continues to want us to pray
over ourselves and over our church.
I mean, we are studying this series on discipleship that really is aiming at that, that we would
get into our souls, that we would understand, not just in our minds, but in our hearts and
in our whole selves, that God actually wants to be present with us.
That we would, that our discipleship wouldn't just be intellectual and God, that it would
be a whole person and mother.
That the discipleship to Jesus wouldn't be about learning information about Jesus, it would
be being with Jesus.
And the Lord bless us and keep us and make this place kind of honest and give us to us.
And you turn this place towards us.
And give us this to our own.
Amen?
All right, like I said, brand new series.
I got a couple of announcements before we like really happen these things.
So, brand new series on discipleship.
Guess what?
It's going to be a three-year-long series.
How many of you guys are excited for that?
I did not think you were going to be excited for that.
All right.
No, it's going to be about three years, but we're going to be the only thing we're covering
for three years.
It's going to be broken up into different sections.
And it's in a partnership with an organization called Practicing the Way.
Practicing the Way is a new church-based curriculum.
And their goal really is to help churches take discipleship beyond its intellect and make
it more of a practice-based thing.
And we'll talk about why that's biblical here in a minute.
Part of the motivation behind the desire of the Christian church, it was a quote from
Dallas Wood, and he said that the church in America, they need a curriculum for Christ's
likeness.
We need a curriculum for Christ's likeness.
Are our worship services, are our small groups, are our passages classes, are our one-on-one
kinds of friends and families, are they helping us to become more like Jesus?
So, throughout this series, we're going to use different levels of content that are borrowed
from this curriculum.
I've never done a church-wide curriculum before, so I just want to give you up-front notice
that some of the content we have is going to be given to us by this curriculum, which means
it might not all be original to me or whoever is up here speaking.
So, some of it is going to be borrowed.
We're not going to be reading transcripts of other people's feelings, but they do give
us transcripts to use.
We're probably not going to use them word-for-word, but I just want you to know, if you hear
something on the internet that sounds like something that I'm saying, I'm not stealing.
It's a word-to-use that will work as a foundation.
This series is built on nine specific practices from the life and teachings of Jesus that go
like this.
Prayer, fasting, community, generosity, Sabbath, that one's going to be fun, solitude, Scripture,
service, and witness.
And so, today, I'm going to write the foundation for this series, and those are the next three
years.
Throughout the time, Lord willing, each one of these will be about four weeks of our attention.
So, for the next eight weeks, we're going to be prayer and fasting, back-to-back.
We probably won't do the other ones back-to-back, but for now, we're going to be prayer and fasting
back-to-back.
My heart is that you would get in a small group to do this with other people.
I think that what happens best in small groups, a small group that I was a part of over
a year ago did the Sabbath, and it's kind of a beta test, and I'll be honest with you,
I haven't still been yet to be good at Sabbath.
So, that's why I was breaking it out over a long period of time, because some of this stuff
takes a long, long time to work out, and I'm assuming.
So, I believe we get the most out of this in community groups.
We are launching 11 small groups next week, which is, yeah, seriously, I cannot thank all
of you enough for the meeting, hosting, helping.
We started small groups last year with three, and this year with 11.
So, we're making room for you.
We want you to be a part of it.
There are groups that are targeted towards some of the priorities in the morning.
I think it's a Friday at 10.
There's a Tuesday at 10.
The Wednesday one is, I think, Wednesday is 10.
10 is all on the website.
Check it all out.
We want you to find that out.
There's new groups that are starting that are wide open, which means, like, you won't be
stepping into something that you're really, you guys are already friends and know each
other.
So, I'd love for you to do that.
Like I said, I'm excited, but I'm also anxious, because I've never done anything like this
before.
You've never done anything like this before.
So, please be gracious with us.
And, as always, like Canvas, if it doesn't work, we'll just stop doing it.
We pretend like we've been started.
So, that's my plan for the next, yeah, for the next nine weeks.
Yeah, okay, let me pray, and then we will hop in.
Father, we are, again, grateful to be in your presence.
Grateful that you promise that when you ask, you send your Holy Spirit, your Holy Spirit
will be active and present in the body of Christ.
We believe, Holy Spirit, you are here this morning.
And we ask that you come, that you continue to do a work in the midst of us, in conversations
in the lobby, in this message, and worship time, and make it on the point of your presence,
that we may be with you.
So, I'm just going to pray for me.
Dear Bibles, we want to turn to Matthew chapter 4.
We'll be in Matthew chapter 4 in a little bit.
Can you say, where do you have an issue you like to watch and or play by?
Okay, that's a good number of you.
I'm going to keep an eye on it in a minute.
Now I know those of you who owe me around with golf, the Pants Recreation Month.
Keep your hands up, keep your hands up now.
Everyone else who knows who Tiger Woods is, raise your name.
All right, pretty much all of us.
Tiger Woods is a massive sports icon.
I follow a podcast that started about, I don't know, 60, 70 years ago, a small podcast.
There's two guys who love golf, who love Tiger Woods, but they're just normal dudes.
They started this podcast because they just wanted to talk about golf.
They weren't getting paid to do it.
And as the years have gone, the podcast has grown.
They've gotten sponsors.
They've gotten, they've gotten, they've gotten like, ordinary people to like, for more, right?
So, they're getting interviews with golfers and all the while continuing to talk about Tiger Woods all the time.
They're getting more exposure, they're getting invited to these golf tournaments so that they can cover them and talk about them on the podcast.
And on one unexpected day, they got a type on their shoulders from one of their connections.
And she said, hey, I'm going to take you over to meet Tiger Woods.
And immediately, they said it's a minute.
They turned their cameras on because they wanted to record for their fans this moment,
this opportunity for them to meet these guys they've been talking about for years.
They posted the video, and as you might expect, if you've ever been in a situation like that,
it was pretty embarrassing.
They were like fumbling over the words, kind of like jaws on the floor, didn't know how to email us with Tiger.
And so, although they could talk about Tiger for hours and hours and hours,
when you're standing in front of him, you're like fish out of the water.
And I think that this story is a helpful illustration.
For what I believe, specifically personally, is one of the biggest problems with what the American church calls discipleship.
Many Christians and churches have made discipleship to Jesus primarily an intellectual deceit.
Our discipleship structures are about learning more information about God,
but are often altogether void of God's presence.
And rarely are effective at helping us become more like Jesus.
Even the way that we preach the gospel affects the way that we disciple one another.
We make the gospel primarily about God saving us from where we're going to go after.
We die rather than God saving us today for real life now.
We've made God's grace to forgive our sins the pinnacle of our salvation.
In reality, God's grace to save your sins as your entrance point to our salvation,
which is followed by an invitation to live in relationship with the God of the universe.
The God who is his father, who loves you, who is inviting you into any relationship.
Dallas Lewis says it this way,
What we present as the gospel will determine what we present as discipleship.
If our message of the gospel is just about saving us from donation when we die,
then how does that change from the way that we think and live today?
Yes, the gospel saves us in eternity,
but it also saves us now as what Jesus calls the abundant glory.
If the gospel we preach is only about what happens to us when we die,
then there really isn't much need for Jesus to change from the ways that he can live today.
I love how that depends on that one's question.
He says,
Jesus is not looking for sins.
He's looking for followers.
And I think,
I don't think it's intentional.
I don't think it's on purpose.
But I think a lot of times the discipleship that we participate in in the American church
is better at making things of the most than it is making followers of Jesus.
It's why many of us who have grown up in the church are really good about talking about the life.
But we're in the prayer closet with ourselves in the presence of God.
Are we tangible?
Are we so welcome to anybody?
Is it natural?
Are we followers of God?
Or are we just becoming the fans of God?
It's the way I always say to disciple other people in Bible college.
I can't tell you the amount of discipleship groups that I was a part of,
where we spent five minutes maybe in prayer and inviting the presence of God to be welcome in the place,
and about two hours of intellectually pontificating about you.
Anybody else like a part of those groups?
Okay.
Not bad.
It's not bad to intellectually study the Scriptures.
These are words that we are meant to read and understand.
And it happens in Hebrew.
These are not bad things.
But I think calling it discipleship distracts us from what biblical discipleship actually is.
The word that we have used as discipleship is a good and fine thing.
Stunning the word of God together in communion.
That's good and fine and should be kind.
But it's not what the Bible calls discipleship.
So my goal here today is to ask us to disconnect the word discipleship from what we call Christian education
and put it in its proper context, to use it the way that the Bible uses it.
Does that make sense?
Okay.
So if discipleship isn't primarily about letting information about Jesus or defending a son of Jesus,
what is biblical discipleship all about?
Again, in order to understand it, directly in the first century Jewish context.
Discipleship was a thing that was happening in first century Judaism.
Every single or, you know, almost every single Jewish boy would have desired to be a disciple.
They started out studying the Old Testament law from a very young age.
And the goal of that pursuit would be that they could become a disciple of a rabbi, of a teacher of the law.
That a desire was that they could disciple under the rabbi.
And discipleship was about following the rabbi around, about living life with the rabbi,
learning the rabbi's teachings, the rabbi's lifestyle, his interpretation of Jewish law.
So for the first purpose that they one day would become a rabbi, a teacher of the law,
this is the framework that Jesus is entering into when he calls his disciples.
The best modern day equivalent to this word would be an apprenticeship.
If somebody coming to a master tradesman and saying, I want to learn your trade,
then I spend time with you, may I be present with you, may I learn from you,
may you teach me how to do those things.
Is that primarily an intellectual pursuit?
Now, it involves intellect, it involves learning things,
but it also involves practicing things.
It involves doing things, it involves watching the master do it,
and you participating in anything.
Well, this was discipleship in the first century.
Discipleship that arise within the master,
learning the knowledge and lifestyle of the rabbi
with the purpose of one day becoming a rabbi themselves.
While Pastor Tyler Staden says,
the biggest difference between Jewish discipleship
and American Christian discipleship
is we use discipleship as an adjective.
It's something that we do.
We participate in discipleship.
We say, who are you discipling?
Who are you being discipled by?
In the first century, they used discipleship as a noun.
It was who you were.
I am a disciple of so-and-so.
So, are we thinking about discipleship in American Christian
as being a disciple and a priest of Jesus?
Are we primarily, indeed, intentional about being with Jesus?
Inviting his presence into our lives.
Is it the desire of our discipleship that we become like Jesus
so that we can do what Jesus did?
Are we disciples?
Is it part of our identity,
or is it just one thing that we participate in?
Does that make sense?
Okay, so this is the context of allowing Christ's invitation to his disciples.
When Jesus invited his disciples to follow him,
they knew what he was doing.
He's a rabbi.
They knew he was inviting them to be his disciples,
to be with them, to follow them, to learn his teachings,
to live the way that he is,
and to ultimately do what he did.
Well, John Mark Homer's definition of discipleship,
he says the call of biblical discipleship
is to be with Jesus,
to become like Jesus,
and to do what Jesus did.
But Matthew, 24, 18 to 20,
one day, as Jesus, a Jewish rabbi,
a teacher,
was walking along the floor of the Jews' gallery,
he saw two brothers,
some men also called Peter,
an angel.
They were throwing a knife into the water,
for they fished for a living.
Jesus called them and said to them,
Come, follow me,
and I will show you how to fish for people.
They left,
they met at once,
and they followed him.
This is Jesus' foundation to his first followers.
Follow me,
and I will make you fish for people.
Amen.
Does that sound weird to anybody else?
Those of you that go into the church,
you're like doing a bunch of translation,
and you're like,
you already got to the end goal.
But for those of us that are reading
and saying to the Bible,
you're like,
this dude's walking around telling people
who's going to make them fish for people.
That is weird.
And you're telling me that discipleship
is to be with this guy,
become like this guy,
and do what he did.
You're telling me that I have to learn
how to fish for people.
Is this some kind of chemistry?
Right?
That's kind of what it seems like.
But in this context,
this phrase was not weird
or unfamiliar to the disciples.
Speaking for people,
there was a cultural idiom
used as great teachers.
They were saying that
great teachers were good
at catching the attention of people.
If you could communicate
your ideology in a creative way,
in an effective way,
if you could make the argument
for the teachings that you were doing,
people would stop,
and they would listen to you,
and you would catch their attention.
Jesus was saying to Peter,
and then he was saying,
I'm going to be a great teacher,
and as you follow me,
I will make you a great teacher.
It's not nearly as weird as it sounds.
It's an invitation to discipleship.
But here's the one thing
I don't want to do in this passage
that's so important to you
and to your life and to my life.
Verse 18,
he called out to Peter and Andrew,
what were they doing?
They were throwing it out of the water,
so what?
Getting space for a living.
Peter and Andrew is far past the age
of getting an apprenticeship to a run by.
They passed their time,
and they studied the law,
and they were deemed not orderly
to become a disciple of a rabbi,
so they went into the profession
of their father.
They're fishing.
How incredible is it
that the best rabbi,
literally God in the flesh,
he goes out to the people,
the rabbis of the day,
the cultural rabbis,
didn't want anything to do with it.
One thing I want to make sure
we don't breeze past
in a short passage
that Jesus called his disciples
in the exact opposite way,
the rabbis of the day,
what is called a new disciple.
There was an imperative,
I'm trying to prove my words
to the rabbi,
and Jesus goes to people
who are choosing themselves
unworthy to the cultural system
of the day,
and he says,
you are worthy of my life.
He says that to you and me,
we are unworthy
of the presence of God.
Unworthy to use the image
of God in his place
and us to participate
in his call
to build the earth,
to cultivate the earth
and sustain the earth,
and yet because of his great grace
and forgiveness and mercy,
he comes to us
when we do not deserve it.
He comes to you
when you do not deserve it
and you cannot admit it,
and he says,
this is one to one minute.
But it requires you
putting down your nets.
You just got to
leave your life behind you.
You got to leave
your old sense of identity
behind your old way
of living behind,
and if you want to be
in the presence of God,
just follow me.
This is the outside
band kingdom of the God.
God invites those of us
who don't be ready
to get in and out of me
to be a part of his kingdom.
In those individuals
that were overlooked
and deemed unworthy
by the cultural system,
Christians,
tax collectors,
and sinners
were all a part of
his kingdom of disciples.
This is at the heart
of faith and inclusion
for you and I
who are all sinners
unworthy of God's grace.
We have revolved against him
and designed our own system
of what has been
according to our own
selfish personalities
and ambitions,
and in the midst
of that rebellion.
And that rejection
of the God
who created you,
God loved you,
he conceived you,
he made a way for you
to experience his presence,
and he's inviting you
to follow him.
No matter,
no matter where you've been,
what you're currently struggling with,
no matter how many times
you've tried and failed,
no matter how unworthy
you might feel this morning,
the God of the universe
is inviting you
to follow him,
to be his disciple.
He wants you.
I think many of us
need to do that
more than once this morning.
He wants you.
This is not something
that he feels like obligated
that he has to do.
This is not something
that he feels like
required to do
by his character
or his nature.
He loves you.
He wants to be with you.
All that is required of us
is that we're going to jump in
and teach all our lives for him.
So,
what's holding you and me
back from this
invitation of the lifetime?
What net are we holding on to
that we refuse
to give in to this invitation?
For the rest of my time,
I really just want to unpack
what it looks like
to become a disciple of Jesus
by being with Jesus,
becoming like Jesus,
and doing what Jesus did.
Does that sound like a plan?
All right,
hold on,
I'm doing that anyway
because I don't do what
it's enough to do.
What's happening here?
Am I all right?
All right.
I don't know.
We'll find out.
All right.
Number one,
to be a disciple of Jesus
is to be with Jesus.
I cannot overstate this enough.
This is the most incredible experience
that you have all
either hear or comprehend
the God of the universe
is ready to be with him.
It's literally what
the entire Bible is all about.
God treats us
for this intimate parent-child relationship
in the garden of Eden.
He invites Adam and Eve
to trust him as his father,
to follow him,
to obey him,
to live in relationship with him,
and everything was perfect.
They rebelled,
and in turn,
we rebelled.
We turned our back on God,
and the rest of the Scriptures
was about God pursuing us
and making a way
to restore us back to himself.
Jesus finished this work,
and we can now have
direct,
unrestricted access
to the Father.
In the presence of God.
This isn't some
still religious requirement.
Being with God,
it's not some
religious requirement
that we should feel
obligated to do.
It's the greatest
privilege any of us
will ever experience.
It's the best invitation
you will ever receive.
I want you
to be with me.
It doesn't just tolerate you,
but do it because
you feel it's obligated.
Again,
Pastor Tyler Staten
says this,
but the number one,
he says,
it's funny,
when he says it,
he says,
after my two decades
of pastoral ministry,
which is how young people
pretend like we're older
than we actually are.
I'm using my second decade
of pastoral ministry right now,
so I'm probably going to use
that line a lot
to build some credibility
with you guys.
He says,
after my second decade
of pastoral ministry,
it's not necessarily,
but the number one obstacle
a modern believer
is facing
when it comes to
discipleship
is the level of God.
He loves you.
He wants you
to be with him.
This is the invitation.
Many of us,
we believe it intellectually.
We read John 3, 16,
and pray it over
and over and over again,
but we struggle
with the rest of it
relationally.
One of the disciples
who have been following
Jesus for a while
asked Jesus,
he says how to pray me.
You guys know
how I follow?
What does he start?
He says,
pray like this
are now in heaven.
This is
God's invitation
for you and I
to enter into his presence.
We enter into his presence
with the most intimate
coming that Jesus
is headed for a child
inside their relationship.
It involves the deepest
sense of parental love.
The God of the universe
wants you to enter
into his presence
with the child
who is fully known
and fully lost
in the presence of God.
I recently became a father
and those of you
that have had young children
know that young children
have been mostly
positioned when it's
mean as 0,000.
Lord can't do anything
for himself.
He can't do anything
for me.
Like literally
this last nine months
like my life
has been about
sacrificing
so that he stays alive.
And yet
thank you.
I appreciate that.
That's a boost
of encouragement
this morning.
And yet
deep within my soul
is an absolute
undeniable
unconditional
I cannot explain to you
how much I want
my baby boy.
He didn't do anything
to me.
to desire
and most of the time
he pushes my buttons
to make me wonder
what in the world
are the days
that I love him
so much to begin with.
I believe
that love
I have for my sons
is part of my
image building nature.
And it's a shadow
of the love
that God has
for you
and for me.
And my love
for my sons
and personal
is personal.
He is inviting you
into this church.
He wants nothing
more than for you
to let all
of your notes
down
and be
with me.
how much
of our disciples
is aimed
on being
in the presence
of God.
Overly,
my favorite
passage of Scripture
in the entire
Bible,
Luke chapter 15.
The story
that I was assigned.
It is the picture
that Jesus wants
you and I
to think about
and really think
about God
as being
a man.
Two sons
in the story
both totally
were going
against the fire.
One is a little
bit more cryptic
than the other.
We don't have time
to cover
the whole story.
A lot of you
know the story.
The one son
essentially says,
I wish you were
dead.
Give me my
inheritance.
I'm going to
go live the way
I want to live.
And I hope
I have a seed.
Goes out,
party,
raising all
his files,
sinning,
and adoption,
waste all
of his father's
money.
And besides,
he's going to
go back
because dad's
a wealthy guy.
And he's like,
oh, I'll just
ask to be his
servant.
And so he's
held down
in shame
and guilt,
knowing that
the last thing
that he said
to his father
is,
I wish you were
dead.
Humbles
himself just
enough to stumble
back with his
help down.
And when he gets
close to the house
to lift his eyes
just a little bit,
the image that he
sees is his
father warning
to him.
puts a ring on the
finger,
a crow from his
back,
kills the
second house,
throws a party
for his son
and has
restored you
and I.
What we told
our father
when we were
bowed and
I'm sorry
is,
I'd rather
rule my
life,
my wife.
I don't want
you to tell me
how to live
my life.
And yet,
for those of us
who have done it
long enough,
we know that it
doesn't work.
And if you
would humble
yourself just
enough,
just enough
to start
that walk
back,
you might be
present in
shame and
guilt and
regret,
you might
feel so
unworthy,
but I promise
you,
if you just
came out
as one
of humility
and turning
yourself back
to God,
what you
will see
is a loving
father running
to him.
The other
son was a lot
more subtle
in his
revaluing
when the
father was
still in the
parties for
the younger
son,
the older
he flips
back up
to the
death
to make
and the
father comes
out.
And the
conversation
may have
essentially
reveals that
the older
brother had
the same
perspective
as his father.
I don't
want to
be with you.
I'm just
biding my
time in here.
I'm being
a good son
so that I
can get
the inheritance
and so that
I can take
my life
and do
what I want.
Do with
it what I
want.
And yet,
the father
invites
that same
son to
you.
When I
want you
more than
many things,
you're
confident.
I want to
be with
you.
This is
the image
Jesus wants
you and I
to have a
God's life
for us.
No matter
who you are,
no matter
what you've
done,
no matter
how much
value you
think your
life has,
the God
of the
universe
wants to
be with
you.
He's
waiting at
the door
with
anticipation.
And I
want to
know,
right now,
depending on
your age
and stage
of life,
you might
be thinking,
when in
the world
am I going
to make
time to
be in
God's
presence?
Anybody
these young
kids like,
you want me
to be with
God?
Both?
Am I the
other one?
Okay.
It's not as
complicated as
you might
think.
I was in
the office
this morning,
mercifuls
when you
worked with
all in
charge of
glory.
Normally,
I get
some alone
time to
pray over
my message
and ask
God to
give me
wisdom.
Glory's
calling all
over me
and I'm
just invading
the places
of God
to be
with us.
It's not,
it doesn't
have to be
some crazy
like,
get in your
closet alone
by yourself
for five
hours.
That's great.
I used to
do that
too.
If it's
possible,
let's just
be with
God
throughout
the day
and write
his
presence
into our
lives.
So,
do we
have an
austere
view of
God's
love?
Do we
understand
what he
did to
make a
way for
us to
be with
him?
Do we
refuse
his
constant
invitation to
be in
his presence?
Is one of
the top
priorities of
our discipleship
to be with
him?
Is our
discipleship
making us
more a
family or a
follower?
discipleship
starts and
ends with
being with
God.
But that's
not the only
element of it.
It starts and
ends with it
to surround the
journey that
it is a
process that
God ultimately
wants us to
grow and
mature and
to be conformed
to the image
of Jesus.
The same way
as I want
for Rory,
right?
It's like Rory
just started
crawling this
past week.
That's a
good thing.
I've been
like anticipating,
excited,
watching him,
learning along,
encouraging him
because I
want him
to grow
and become
the man
that God
wants him
to be.
The same
is true
of those
children of
God.
We are
welcomed,
loved,
unconditionally
children of
God.
What the
Father wants
for us is
that we
would mature
into the
lifestyle that
he has
designed
for.
Jesus'
lifestyle is
the perfect
image of
what it
looks like
to be
human.
And so
if we
are going
to mature
into the
person that
God wants
us to be,
we are
going to
mature into
the image
of Jesus.
One aspect
of discipleship
is being
with Jesus
so that we
might become
like Jesus.
Romans 8,
29.
I mean,
there's one
people in
here that
are really
excited about
him,
okay?
For those
who he
foreknew,
he also
predestined
what?
He wanted
to predestine
us to be.
He predestined
us to be
conformed to
the image
of his
Son,
so that
Jesus
would be
firstborn
among
many
brothers and
sisters.
When you
become a
child of
God,
God's
endestination
for you.
It's to
be conformed
to the
image of
Jesus.
That is
what he
wants for
each and
every follower
of Jesus.
The ultimate
aim of
discipleship is
to become
like the
minister and
to do
what the
minister did.
If you're
spending time
in the
presence of
God,
but it
isn't
transforming
you into
a person
of
sacrificial
laws and
humility,
you're doing
the wrong.
Okay?
This often
gets misconstrue
by religious
teachings as a
set of rules
we have to
follow to
make God
happy.
Instead,
it is an
invitation to
our loving
Father to
grow in
maturity and
to experience
the life
that we
designed to
utilize the
abundant
life.
for the
steadest
side of
fleshly
desires that
lead to
death and
embrace the
lifestyle and
teachings of
grace that
lead to
abundant
life.
Pastor
Tyler,
when it
certainly
comes to
the
means,
we don't
do that.
If you
want to
experience
the
life of
Jesus,
you have
to take
on the
life
domain of
Jesus.
This is
discipleship.
And we
become
like Jesus,
a patient,
sacrificial
law,
humility,
a person
who prioritizes
coming with
the Father.
This is
why we
spend so
much time
over the
next few
years doing
details into
the teachings
and practices
of Jesus.
So many
of these
practices are
counter-cultural.
And I think
most of us,
we don't even
realize how
discipled we
are by our
culture.
We're so
discipled by
just the
rhythms and
patterns of
our lives.
We're so
busy,
we're so
distracted,
and we're so
overwhelmed with
life, and
oftentimes it's
because we
are living
life the
way that
the culture
is living
life.
The culture
has been
disused by
the enemy
of God,
who all
we want
to do
is destroy
and destroy
your life.
These
practices are
designed for
us to take
a time and
to invite
God's presence
into our
lives and to
expose us to
the things that
we're doing
that the
enemy is
using to
distract us
and to
ultimately
destroy
the world.
Think about
just what
Jesus established
as an example.
The census
established.
Taking 24
hours to
not do
anything that
you feel like
you have to
do, to
rest, to
invite God's
presence into
your life, what
might God say
to you in
those 24
hours?
What might
God really
see you?
I mean, I
think I'm
Sabbath for
over a
year now, and
maybe God
writes three
times in
like 60
some weeks.
I'm not
speaking as a
person who's
pressing it,
but what I'm
saying is,
once we just
ahead, just
daily steps
into these
practices that
God might
have used to
reveal to
us, the
others of
our hearts,
the things
that are
keeping us
from being
performed
into
measurement.
The next
eight weeks
I'm going to
declare
that I've
seen
common
cultural
and active
defiance
on self
alignment.
It's me
coming to
God and
saying,
I can't
do it.
I don't
have the
power.
I am
never
strong.
And our
culture
tells us,
you are
strong.
You can
do it.
make your
life exactly
what you
want.
But even
as you
can't,
you can
at least
create a
fake life
on Instagram.
You're going to
see people
think you're
pressing it.
And
when you
stop and
enter the
presence of
God.
It's an
asking for
financial
personalities.
Fasting is
an asking
rebellion.
It's a
flesh and
such
desires.
These are
all
activities that
God can
use to
perform
us into
his image.
This is
the goal
for
us to lose.
This
practice-based
discipleship is
why the
early believers,
one of my
favorite parts,
they didn't
call themselves
Christians.
You know
what the
early
followers called
themselves?
Followers of
the way,
right?
Why?
Because they
embraced Jesus'
teaching as a
lifestyle, a
way to live, and
experience the
life that God
wanted them to
live.
But as they
were following
the way, the
teachings of
Jesus, the
practices of
Jesus, as
they were being
disciples of
Jesus, even
after he had
gone to
heaven, the
never
will happen.
This will
happen when
they were
following the
way of
Jesus.
They became
like Jesus.
Literally.
And so
everyone around
them started
calling them
Christians, or
little Christ.
It was meant
to be a
derogatory
term.
It was meant
to say,
essentially, you
are a
lunatic who
are following
a failed,
crucified
rabbi, but
for us,
he's become a
boss of
father, we
will, that
identifies us
with the
risen state
of the
man.
If we
embrace the
way of
Jesus, the
lifestyle and
the teachings
of Jesus, I
believe that
the Holy Spirit
will use that
to perform us
to the image
of Jesus, who
will become
more
righteous.
Unfortunately,
now it is when
people are
referring to
someone as a
Christian, it
has more to
do with an
intellectual
decision or
moral ethics
than they
are going
to do.
My desire
to life
church is that
we would
recommend
the
innocent
reason for
being called
Christians.
But we
would embrace
the lifestyle
and teachings
of Jesus, and
through embracing
those lifestyles
and teachings
we need to
form to
his image
and the
world around
us would
see us as
literally
Christ.
Is there
the sacrificial
process transforming
you into a
Christian sacrificial
variety of
unity?
Are you more
patient,
kind,
good,
safe,
gentle,
and self-control
than before?
Are you
spending more
time learning
about God
or are you
prioritizing
time with
him?
Is that
decision making
you more
fulfilling him
or more
fulfilling him?
Do you spend
more time
admiring his
teachings or
emulating his
lifetime?
This one's,
this one's
about amazing.
Do I spend
more time
admiring
his teachings?
I've got
books full of
commentaries on
my shelves,
logo software
on my computer.
I love to
admire the
teachings of
God.
It's not
big.
But if I do
it void
of a real
tangible
relationship with
the Holy
Spirit,
it's
inviting and
into my
life to
transform me
into a
person of
love from
us.
This is the
point of
discipleship
that we
together.
Is any
man you
feel guilty?
Like me?
Jesus says
good, I'll
say please
don't.
The goal
is not that
you would
feel guilty
in a lot
of ways.
This journey
is a
lifelong
prophecy.
It's
really
to me.
Most of
my
experience
has
prioritized
intellectual
discipleship.
This is
only the
lifelong
journey
that
God
has
embraced
and
we should
be patient
and gracious
with ourselves
because God
is
proud of
and we're
going to
bring
Jesus
to accept
love.
He's
like a
father.
He's
better than
any earthly
father you
should ever
imagine.
I know a
lot of
us have
dragons with
bad earthly
fathers.
Think about
the best
father you've
ever seen
that you
said,
I wish
that guy
was my
dad.
And that
kind of
skills and
comparison
to the
love the
father has
for you.
Be gracious
with yourself.
Take time.
We're going
to take four
weeks to talk
about prayer.
We're going
to talk about
different
types of prayer,
different types
of prayer.
We're going
to invite
you into
it.
I love
John Mark
Homer,
he's done
this at
his church.
He says,
we make
invitations,
you make
decisions.
We make
suggestions,
you make
decisions.
None of
this is like
religious,
you've got to
do it.
This is an
invitation for
you to take
steps in your
relationship with
God.
every time
a rabbi
accepted
the
disciple
is
the
goal
that
one
day
they
would
become
a
rabbi.
And that
a way
to
visit
the
discipleship.
So the
discipleship
process about
being with
Jesus so that
we might
become like
Jesus so that
we might do
what Jesus
did.
Anybody else
intimidated?
Think about
what Jesus did.
He healed the
sick,
incited the
blind,
cast out
demons,
raised people
from the
dead,
and on
the
least
goes.
And I
know what
you're thinking,
but he was
God.
You know my
theology from
the room?
Not so fast,
right?
Jesus laid
down his
defined
privileges to
become human.
Everything he
did on earth,
he did as a
human,
totally relying
on the
power of the
Holy Spirit.
He sent
his disciples
out with the
same power,
and guess
what they
did?
The same
stuff.
He says
to tell us
he will
do his
blood,
his spirit,
and we
will do
even greater
things than
you did.
But,
I know
that this
is what
I'm losing
you,
right?
Right?
Are you
going to
try to
make us
become some
crazy,
serious
magic church
that
regularly
prays for
and expects
God to do
the miraculous
things on
Earth as
it is in
heaven?
Yes.
But that's
for the
future
sermon series.
I was like,
I think I
should be
honest with you
that I'm
going to
mess with
the rules.
We will
maybe wait
into that
later,
and it'll
be fun.
And maybe
we won't
need more
chairs.
We brought
more chairs,
but maybe
we won't
need more
chairs.
But for
this morning,
I want to
focus on one
primary thing
that Jesus
did in the
history of
ministry.
The one
primary thing
that Jesus
did in the
history of
ministry.
He made
disciples.
It's why
we're here
today,
because Jesus
effectively made
disciples.
He spent
time with
him as
pastors.
He became
like him
and he
worked in
life.
and he
invited
others to
do the
same.
Not only
did he
make
disciples,
but he
commissioned
all of
those who
would follow
him to
make
disciples.
You see
the
trick to
say,
follow me,
do with
me,
become like
and do
what I
do.
Linder the
in the
kingdom.
I
will show you
for people.
After three
years of being
with Jesus
and becoming
a life
to himself,
Jesus comes
to them and
tells them the
thing that they
don't want to
hear.
I'm not here.
But you're
ready.
I'm going to
stand my
spirit
power.
And you
are going
to make
disciples.
You are
going to
do what I
do.
This is a
radical
fall of
discipleship.
And it's
the reason
that followers
of the
way have
increased
from 120
years of
individuals
being in
our own
Jerusalem
in the
first
century to
millions of
followers
across
history and
geographies.
The reason
you and
I are in
this
language is
because
disciples of
Jesus,
the time
with Jesus
became like
Jesus and
made more
disciples of
Jesus.
I'm only
for our
disciples to
process,
for the
process into
the presence
of God,
conformance
into the
image of
God,
but it's
the result
of us
inviting
others to
do the
same.
I know
this might
seem overwhelming
and for all
it's never
yet been
used.
I don't
ever use
what it's
kind of
for you.
At the
end of the
day,
this is
far more
simple
than to
make it.
It's as
simple as
prioritizing
the
name of
Jesus,
gracefully
letting the
Holy Spirit
transform into
a notion of
Jesus through
the prized
Holy Spirit
and just
inviting your
son to send
the members
forward to
his neighbors,
enemies,
to experience
this being
life-based
woman color
that you've
experienced
by just
laying down
your nets
and accepting
the invitation
of the
father of the
universe.
Holy Spirit
says that
every follower
of Jesus
has a
relationship
wherever
they go.
We have
the opportunity
to be
like Jesus
rabbi
and sort
of send
their members
and aid
their solar
Christian
forms.
Are we
fighting
Jesus
in a
converted
way?
and inviting
others to
follow him
as we
do.
This is
my invitation.
our
invitation.
Be
as Jesus.
Become
right to
Jesus.
And do
what he
needs.
This is
telling most
of us
many of us
we miss
out on the
soul
of this
invitation.
For one
reason or
another,
maybe you
don't
consider
you've
misunderstood
the invitation
of Jesus
to one
family that
is believing
in him so
that you
won't go
to hell
when you
don't.
These
miss
them
is
the
invitation.
Because
what
are your
things
made you
more of a
thing
than a
follower?
We
encourage
us and
to send
that
out of
ideology
and receive
this
invitation
not just
to eternal
salvation,
but it is
a part
of the
to a
friendship
under
Jesus
as
the
one
and
change
human
in the
of this.
Maybe you're
really enjoying
the pleasures
of this
world.
I'm so
sure that
what you
mean
has all
for
to spend
it.
I don't
know if
there's
anything I
can say
this morning
to persuade
you.
All I
know is
one day
that a
decision
will persuade
you
going to
China.
And when
that time
comes,
when you
get rock
bottom,
when you
be in
charge of
your
life,
if you
are working
out the
way that
you thought
it would,
we are
going to
be here
with hope
on us.
I'll tell
so many
of you
that that
day is
today.
Maybe
you're
in here
and you're
living
a bubble
life,
and you're
wanting to
church and
one thing
in your
home,
selfish and
sinful
life,
and for
so long
you've
just assumed
that God
was done
with you.
You've
just been
going
through
the
motions,
complaining
in church
so that no
one knows
that you
haven't
come in
the
presence
of God
for months
or even
years.
And I'm
going to
hear this
of you
saying this
this morning,
is you
the case
of this
thing?
Is God
of the
universe
disembarking
you to
bring to
this
presence
as a
life?
person
of you
knows
who
loves
you.
Save
some
Jesus
rest.
In your
place
for you
to
so that
you
might
have
free
outside
of
out
so
you
can't
out of
this
life.
Instead
of the
heart
frame
of our
lessons
that
we
have
taken
upon
the
offer.
I
don't
do
a
fair
offer.
So I
would
like
to
give
this
a
homework.
Is
that
okay?
I'm
going to
give
a
homework.
you
can
do
it.
Again,
I
make
suggestions
and you
make
decisions.
I
would
love
it
if
you
would
take
some
time
maybe
once
a
day
this
week
to
read
Luke
chapter
or
if
that
story
probably
was
something
that
I
told
you
about.
Read
it out loud.
Have
it read
over you.
Maybe
use
audio.
However
useful
and
responsible.
Maybe
use
the
process
of
left
field
to
do
that.
God
has
time
and
space
to
speak
you
through
his
word.
This
week
my
phrase
for
least
one
of
us
is
that
we
would
understand
the
love
to
follow
the
preserved
image
to
of
the
system.
This
question
was
saying
we'll
get
out
here.
Father
we
are
prone
to
wander.
And
we
all
have
different
temptations
and
desires
that
when
you
wander
are
scared
prone
to
wander
towards
being
your
son
and
rather
being
your
son
of
you.
it's
so
easy
for
me
to
talk
about
you.
And
often
it's
hard
right
session.
For
me
that's
because
I
often
misunderstand
how
much
you
really
left
me.
God
I
know
that
throughout
this room
there's
a number
of
struggles
and
challenges
temptations
that are
causing
us
to
wander.
And
a number
of
rise
and
regrace
from
living
that are
perpetuating
that
decision.
So I
just pray
for each
person
in this
room
this
morning
and
this
person
watching
all
of
you.
If
your
Holy
Spirit
would
reveal
to them
a lie
that they're
believing
about
God
that's
causing
them
to
walk
away
and
instructing
Jesus
words
that
might
each
person
in this
room
and
the
one
of
God's
love.